Register of the Japan, Koshikan (Korea) records
Hoover Institution Archives
- File of documents, (Meiji 40-nen monjo tsuzurikomi), 1907; 120 frames. (Folder 275)
- Confidential reports of the Japanese Legation in Korea, (Meiji 40-nen kimitsu hokoku), (1908-20) 1907; 288 frames. (Folder 276)
- Documents relating to the contract concerning ginseng fields and the agreement on ginseng monopoly, (Meiji 35, 36-nen sampo keiyaku oyobi sansei kyotei), (1902-9) 1902, 1903; 8 frames. (Folder 278)
- Telegrams received by the Japanese Legation in Korea in August and September, (Meiji 41-nen denju ji hachigatsu itaru kugatsu), 1908; 195 frames. (Folder 294)
- Documents relating to the records of the Korean envoy [to China], (Meiji 38-nen Kankoku hoshi kiroku), 1905; 183 frames. (Folder 345)
- Secret reports of the Japanese Gendarmerie in Korea, January and February, (Meiji 42-nen kempeitai kimitsu hokoku ji ichigatsu itaru nigatsu), (1901-1) 1909; 263 frames. (Folder 405)
- Ditto -- February and March, (1909-36) 1909.; 135 frames. (Folder 406)
- Ditto--, April, 1909.; 407 frames. (Folder 407)
- Ditto--, May, 1909.; 148 frames. (Folder 408)
- Ditto --, (1909-30) June, 1909; 198 frames. (Folder 409)
- Ditto--, (1909-32) July, 1909.; 158 frames. (Folder 410)
- Ditto--, (1909-36) Aug. 1909.; 137 frames. (Folder 411)
- Ditto-, (1909-36) Sept. 1909.; 137 frames. (Folder 412)
- Documents relating to the establishment of a branch unit of the Japanese Gendarmerie in Kando (Chientao), (Meiji 40-nen Kanto kempeitai shubi setchi no ken), 1907; 165 frames. (Folder 413)
- Documents relating to the liquidation of the Chinnamp'o Fishing Company, (Meiji 42-nen Chinnampo Suisan Kaisha shobun no ken), 1909; 163 frames. (Folder 414)
- Reports of the Japanese Gendarmerie detachments in Korea concerning local conditions, (Meiji 42-nen kempei buntai chiho jokyo hokoku), 1909; 32 frames. (Folder 415)
- Documents relating to press censorship, (Meiji 42-nen shimbun kiji keisai kinshi no ken), 1909; 44 frames. (Folder 416)
- Documents relating to the recruitment for the Salvation Army, (Meiji 42-nen Kyuseigun boshu ni kansuru ken), 1909; 192 frames. (Folder 417)
- Confidential reports of the Headquarters of Japanese Police Superintendents in Korea, (Meiji 42-nen Keishicho kimitsu hokoku jugatsu), (1909-40) Oct. 1909; 15 frames. (Folder 418)
- Documents relating to the conditions on the western bank of the Yalu River and the Investigation Report of Natural Resources in the Ussuri River Region, or Report of Investigation of Natural Resources in the northeastern and southern parts of Manchuria and the Ussuri River region. (Meiji 40-nen Oryokko seihenkai jokyo oyobi Usurii chiho shigen chosahyo or Manshu tohakubu oyobi nambu Usurii chiho shigen chosahyo), (1908-13) 1907; 105 frames. (Folder 419)
- Documents relating to the border violations by armed Chinese, (Meiji 42-nen buso Shinkokajin ekkyo ni kansuru ken), 1909; 217 frames. (Folder 420)
- Confidential documents of the Headquarters of Japanese Police Superintendents in Korea, (Meiji 42-nen Keishicho kimitsu hokoku kugatsu), (1909-7) Sept. 1909; 68 frames. (Folder 421)
- Documents relating to rafting along-the Yalu River. 1909 or documents relating to the injury of raftsmen along the Yalu River, (Meiji 42-nen Oryokko gan ikada ni kansuru ken or Oryokko ryuiki ikadafu higai no ken), (1909-26) 1909; 120 frames. (Folder 422)
- Documents relating to the floating of Japanese loans for the construction of railroads, telegraph lines, and port facilities [in Korea], (Tetsudo densen kaiko kashikin), (1894-14) 1894 (Folder 501)
  Documents relating to loans to Japanese companies for the construction of the Seoul-Pusan and Seoul-Inchon railroads; the installation of telegraph lines; and the opening of Pusan, Inchon, and W0nsan.
- Documents relating to the Seoul-Shin'iju and the Seoul-W0nsan rail-roads, (Keigi tetsudo oyobi Keigen tetsudo), (1900-17) 1900 (Folder 502)
- Copies of translated telegrams, (Denshin yakubun), (1901-12) 1901; 242 frames. (Folder 503)
  Translations of European-language telegrams exchanged between the Japanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs with Japanese diplomatic posts abroad.
- Copies of translated telegrams [relating to the] Manchurian problem, (Denshin yakubun Manshu mondai), (1901-13) 1901; 71 frames. (Folder 504)
  Translations of English-language () telegrams exchanged between the Japanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs and Japanese diplomatic posts relating to the Manchurian problem.
- Documents relating to communications between Russia and Korea, (Ro-Kan denshin tsushin tsuren), (1910-20) 1901; 241 frames. (Folder 505)
  Documents relating to the establisyment of Korean control over Russian-installed telegraph lines in northern Korea; wireless communications and telegraph lines between Pusan and Masan; Section 2 of Article III of the Lobanov-Yamagata agreement of 1896 concerning the installation of telegraph lines between Seoul and the Russian border; the installation of telegraph lines by the Russians from the Russian border to Ky0ng'hung; the Anglo-Japanese Alliance and its effects on Russo-Japanese relations in Korea; and a comparative chart of telegraph rates between Japan and Korea.
- Telegraphic correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with Japanese consulates in Korea and with others, (Kaku ryujikan sonota orai dempo), (1902-7) 1902; 44 frames. (Folder 506)
- Confidential correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with Japanese consulates in Korea, (Kimitsu kakkan orai), (1903-10) 1903; 66 frames. (Folder 507)
  Documents relating to clashes between Japanese residents and Russian soldiers in Korea; Russian residents in the Tumen River area; the withdrawal of Russian marines from Yulkumi; the Customs Chief in Masan G. H. Arnous; rumors concerning Russian naval maneuvers near Korea; riots in the S0njin and Kilchu areas; and reports on S0ngjin and Ky0ng'hung.
- Telegrams sent to Japanese consulates in Korea, (Kakkan oden), (1903-14) 1903; 152 frames. (Folder 508)
- Telegrams received from Japanese consulates in Korea; (Kakkan raiden), (1903-21) 1903; 24 frames. (Folder 509)
  Telegrams received by the Japanese Legation in Korea from the Japanese consulates in Inchon, Pyongyang, Iju and other cities.
- Documents relating to Korean-Chinese relations, (Kan-Shin kankei), (1904-13) 1904 (Folder 510)
- Correspondence with the Japanese consulates in Seoul and Inchon. Telegrams of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Japanese consulates in W0nsan and S0ngjin, (Keijo, Jinsen orai. Genzan, Joshin den orai), (1904-21) (Folder 511)
- Documents relating to Japanese residents in Korea who distinguished themselves during the [Russo-Japanese] War, (Sen'eki koro kyoryusha kankei 1904-1905), (1904-27) 1904-1905; 13 frames. (Folder 512)
- Confidential correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Home Office, (Kimitsu honsho orai), (1905-10) 1905 (Folder 513)
- Documents relating to the adviser to the Ministry of the Royal Household Legendore, (Kunaifu komon Risendoru), (1906-11) 1906 (Folder 514)
- Correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Home Office, (Honsho oraishin), (1906-19) 1906; 128 frames. (Folder 515)
- Documents relating to the matters handled by the Department of Foreign Affairs [of the Residency-General], (Gaimubu toriatsukai), (1906-26) 1906-7 (Folder 516)
- Documents relating to the protection of Koreans in Kando (Chientao), (Kanto Kammin hogo ni kansuru ken), (1906-27) 1906-07; 164 frames. (Folder 517)
- Confidential documents relating to Japanese nationals in Korea, Yi Ik - ho and another Korean, (Hompojin kimitsu Ri Yoku-ko hoka ichimei kankei), (1906-33) 1906; 42 frames. (Folder 518)
- Documents relating to "Your telegram No: 196" (Kiden dai 196 go ni kanshite), (1907-5); 172 frames. (Folder 519)
- Copies of telegrams received [from the Resident-General during his tour], (Shutchochu denju denshin hikae), (1907-24) 1907; 129 frames. (Folder 520)
- File on scientific matters, (Gakujutsu tsuzuri), (1907-29) 1907-9 (Folder 521)
- Copies of telegrams received by the Japanese Legation in Korea, May, (Denju hikae), (1908-3) 1908; 58 frames. (Folder 522)
- Miscellaneous file, (Zakken tsuzuri), (1908-10) 1908 (Folder 523)
- Documents relating to Chriatian churches in Korea, (Kirisutokyo) jokyo), (1908-20) 1908; 119 frames. (Folder 524)
- Documents relating to the control of illegal fishing by the Chinese [in Korean waters], (Shinkoku mitsuryo torishimari ni kansuru ken), (1909-2) 1909; 163 frames. (Folder 525)
- Miscellaneous documents relating to foreigners [in Korea] (public speeches made by Americans), (Gaikokujin zakken. Beikokujin enzetsu no ken), (1909-22) 1909 (Folder 526)
- Documents of the Residency-General, (Tokanfu monjo), (1909-31) 1909; 77 frames. (Folder 527)
- Confidential documents of the Japanese Gendarmerie in Korea relating to the personal records of Korean officials, (Kempeitai kimitsu monjo. Kan kanjin no keireki ippan), (1909-32) 1909; 152 frames. (Folder 528)
- Confidential documents of the Chief of the Japanese Gendarmerie in Korea, (Kempeitaicho kimitsu), (1909-33) 1909; 98 frames. (Folder 529)
- Confidential documents of the Headquarters of Japanese Police Superintendents in Korea, (Keishicho kimitsu monjo), (1909-40) Sept. -Oct., 1909; 89 frames. (Folder 530)
- Confidential correspondence received from various Japanese diplomatic posts, (Kimitsu shoho raishin), (SY1894-4) 1894 (Folder 531)
  Documents relating to the Tonghak Rebellion; Chinese military aid to Korea; the purchase of land for the Japanese settlement in Pusan; Yuan Shih-k'ai's statement relating to the Korean question; and the An Ky0ng-su group.
- Confidential correspondence to and from the Home Office, (Kimitsu honsho orai), (SY1896-2) 1896 (Folder 532)
  Documents relating to Japanese loans to Korea;Yi Chun-yong's education in Japan; Korean government bonds; Japanese garrisons along the Seoul-Pusan railroad; the King's temporary refuge at the Russian Legation; political, social, and economic conditions in Seoul; the Seoul-Inchon railroad concession; and the establishment of a Japanese school in Seoul.
- Miscellany, (Zatsu), (SY1899-7) 1899 (Folder 533)
  Documents relating to ginseng trade; Japanese rights in connection with the Russo-Korean telegraph agreement; the Ch'ang'w0n gold mine; timber concessions to a Chinese-Japanese company Yoshimori Koshi; and financial conditions in Korea. Research report on the Korean Bureau of Foreign Exchange.